<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>Chopin&apos;s Legacy and the Origins of the Competition (ft. Aleksander Laskowski)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YpL7HpWucIQ</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YpL7HpWucIQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 3 Oct 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[OPUS INDEX: https://index.chopinpodcast.com
MERCH: https://www.chopinpodcast.com/merch

Season 2 Episode 7 Variety Show: FULL AUDIO COMING SOON

0:00 The biggest classical music event in the world
0:56 The history of the Chopin Competition
4:08 Chopin: A man of the past, present, and future
7:55 What Chopin has in common with Beethoven
10:16 A tribute to Garrick Ohlsson
13:20 The camaraderie of competitions
17:55 Janusz Olejniczak, R.I.P.
20:39 Chopin’s Polish Song, Op. 74 No. 17
26:32 The importance of the US Chopin Foundation
28:17 The guardian angel and patron saint of The Chopin Podcast

This podcast is produced in partnership with the Chopin Foundation of the United States, which presents the National Chopin Competition every 5 years. For more, visit https://chopin.org

The Chopin Foundation is a national non-profit organization founded by its President, Blanka A. Rosenstiel in 1977, and inspired by the first US Chopin Competition she presented in Miami in 1975. Support the Chopin Foundation: https://chopin.org/donate

Access bonus scenes from interviews with Alek Laskowski and other guests:
https://patreon.com/BenLaude

https://www.facebook.com/chopinpodcast
https://www.facebook.com/benlawdy
https://www.instagram.com/benlawdy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Don&apos;t U.S. Territories Have the Same Rights as States? | Civics Made Easy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iCxL6y94Nu0</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iCxL6y94Nu0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Did you know America has ‘territories’ with thousands, if not millions, of U.S. citizens living on them? But not every territory grants U.S citizenship to those born there. And even so, citizens living in territories don’t have the same rights as citizens living in states. Ben Sheehan explains the history, legality, and tax status of U.S. territories – and whether or not they should become states.

🔔 Don’t forget to like, subscribe, and hit the bell so you don’t miss future episodes of Civics Made Easy on PBS.

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#usgovernment #guam #puertorico #civics 

Civics Made Easy
Hosted by Ben Sheehan, breaks down the complex world of American government and civic participation. Each episode transforms intricate concepts into clear, digestible lessons, equipping viewers with the essential knowledge to actively participate in their democracy. Designed to empower and inform, the series makes understanding civics both accessible and engaging for all.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Order Of The Golden Dawn: The Mysterious Victorian Occult Society</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bXQdhJGf6JY</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bXQdhJGf6JY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 21:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Strangest Secret Society Of The Victorian Era

The Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn emerged in late 19th-century London, capitalizing on a spiritual void created by the Industrial Revolution. Founded by William Wescott, William Robert Woodman, and Samuel Liddell MacGregor Mathers, the secret society claimed its authority came from mysterious "Cipher Manuscripts" and the "Secret Chiefs," ascended beings who provided them with ancient knowledge. The order's curriculum, a blend of various mystical traditions like Hermetic Qabalah and alchemy, attracted many notable figures, including poet W.B. Yeats, and was unique for its inclusion of women. However, the society's internal rivalries, particularly a power struggle involving its most infamous member, Aleister Crowley, led to its eventual demise by 1939. Despite its short lifespan, the Golden Dawn's legacy continues to influence modern occultism, with key figures shaping our understanding of magic and mysticism.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Life on Mars Will DOOM Humanity</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PuHrtlJPk3o</link><author>PBS Space Time</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PuHrtlJPk3o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 20:15:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7_gcs09iThXybpVgjHZ_7g">PBS Space Time</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Click this link: https://www.boot.dev/?promo=spacetime and use my code SPACETIME to get 25% off your first payment for boot.dev

Recent findings have brought us closer than we’ve ever been to confirming life beyond the Earth. As we wait for confirmation or otherwise, let’s think about what this will tell us about life everywhere, and also about our own imminent destruction.

Sign Up on Patreon to get access to the Space Time Discord!
https://www.patreon.com/pbsspacetime

Check out the Space Time Merch Store
https://www.pbsspacetime.com/shop

Sign up for the mailing list to get episode notifications and hear special announcements!
https://mailchi.mp/1a6eb8f2717d/spacetime

Search the Entire Space Time Library Here: https://search.pbsspacetime.com/

Hosted by Matt O'Dowd
Written by Matt O'Dowd 
Post Production by Leonardo Scholzer, Yago Ballarini & Stephanie Faria
Directed by Andrew Kornhaber
Associate Producer: Bahar Gholipour
Executive Producer: Andrew Kornhaber
Executive in Charge for PBS: Maribel Lopez
Director of Programming for PBS: Gabrielle Ewing
Assistant Director of Programming for PBS: John Campbell

Spacetime is a production of Kornhaber Brown for PBS Digital Studios.
This program is produced by Kornhaber Brown, which is solely responsible for its content.
© 2025 PBS. All rights reserved.

End Credits Music by J.R.S. Schattenberg: https://www.youtube.com/user/MultiDroideka

Space Time Was Made Possible In Part By: 

Big Bang
Alexander Tamas
Juan Benet
Mark Rosenthal
Morgan Hough
Peter Barrett
Tj Steyn
Vinnie Falco

Supernova
Ethan Cohen
Glenn Sugden
Grace Biaelcki
Mark Heising
Stephen Wilcox
Tristan Lucian Claudius Aurelius Tyacke

Hypernova
Alex Kern
Ben Delo
Cal Stephens
chuck zegar
David Giltinan
Dean Galvin
Donal Botkin
Gregory Forfa
Jesse Cid Dyer
John R. Slavik
Justin Lloyd
Kenneth See
Massimiliano Pala
Michael Tidwell
Mike Purvis
Paul Stehr-Green
Scott Gorlick
Scott Gray
Spencer Jones
Stephen Saslow
Stephen Spidle
Thomas Mouton
Zachary Haberman
Антон Кочков
Daniel Muzquiz

Gamma Ray Burst
Alex Gan
Aaron Pinto
Adrien Molyneux
Almog Cohen
Anthony Leon
Arko Provo Mukherjee
Ayden Miller
Ben McIntosh
Bradley Jenkins
Bradley Ulis
Brandon Lattin
Brian Cook
Bryan White
Christopher Wade
Chuck Lukaszewski
Collin Dutrow
Craig Falls
Craig Stonaha
Dan Warren
Daniel Donahue
Daniel Jennings
Daron Woods
Darrell Stewart
David Johnston
Diana S Poljar
Doyle Vann
Eric Kiebler
Eric Raschke
Faraz Khan
Frederic Simon
Harsh Khandhadia
Ian Williams
Isaac Suttell
James Trimmier
Jeb Campbell
Jeremy Soller
Jerry Thomas
jim bartosh
John Anderson
John De Witt
John Funai
John H. Austin, Jr.
Joseph Salomone
Junaid Ali
Justin Waters
Kacper Cieśla
Kane Holbrook
Keith Pasko
Kent Durham
Koen Wilde
Kurt Gottselig
Lori Ferris
Marcelo Garcia
Marion Lang
Mark Daniel Cohen
Mark Delagasse
Matt Quinn
Matthew Johnson
Michael Barton
Michael Clark
Michael Lev
Michael Purcell
Nathaniel Bennett
Nick Hoffenstoffer III
Nicolas Katsantonis
Param Saxena
Paul Wood
Rad Antonov
Reuben Brewer
Richard Steenbergen
Robert DeChellis
Ross Story
Russell Moore
Sandhya Devi
Satwik Pani
Sean Owen
Shane Calimlim
SilentGnome
Sound Reason
Steffen Bendel
Steven Giallourakis
Terje Vold
Thomas Dougherty
Todd J Lerner
Tomaz Lovsin
Tybie Fitzhugh
Vlad Shipulin
WILLIAM HAY III
Zac Sweers]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Asking Pete Buttigieg about Israel &amp; Palestine</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/AuHtAcN-DXo</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AuHtAcN-DXo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 19:59:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>History VS Narrative: King &amp; Conqueror Interview</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2b0V6VlrwqM</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2b0V6VlrwqM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 19:00:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[How do you balance retelling a well-known part of history while still creating a compelling narrative and new perspective? And what do you do if you break your collarbone while doing so?

We interviewed actor James Norton and producer Kitty Kaletsky to discuss their historical BBC drama 'King and Conqueror', including their creative liberties within the story of William the Conqueror and King Harold Godwinson. 
 
0:00 Introduction
0:54 Why Did This Story Take So Long to Tell?
2:10 Expanding and Conflating the Timeline: Why Start Before 1066?
3:32 Representing History: Artistic Freedom & Accuracy
5:58 Meet The Godwins: A Medieval "Succession"
9:53 Costume and Production: Building an 11th Century World in Iceland
11:59 Emma of Normandy: The Queen at the Centre of the Conflict
14:03 The Great Moustache Debate
15:05 Bringing the Viking Harald Hardrada to Life
17:16 Filming the Battle of Hastings With a Broken Collarbone
22:32 The Magic of Filming an Epic Battle Scene
24:51 The Stunt Training & Icelandic Naked Showers
26:50 The Mystery of King Harold's Death
28:31 Team Harold vs. Team William: Who Was the Rightful Heir?

All episodes of King and Conqueror are now available to stream on BBC iPlayer: 

https://www.bbc.co.uk/iplayer/episodes/m0024pyz/king-conqueror

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The surprising origins of Sober October #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/hoKmPyrG9ps</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hoKmPyrG9ps?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 18:17:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It’s Sober October, during which manosphere influencers like Joe Rogan and cancer research advocates abstain from alcohol — for very different reasons. One group wants to raise awareness about alcohol’s health risks. The other is all about short-term gains. But together, they represent one of the most remarkable cultural trends of the moment: Americans are drinking less alcohol. 

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Neanderthal &amp; Homo sapien sitting in a tree! 😏 #human #anthropology #science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Gdrv5sQ49cE</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Gdrv5sQ49cE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 17:00:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Find out where to watch Human in your region 👉 https://www.bbcearth.com/shows/human

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Measuring the Universe&apos;s Expansion</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/cp0le2TusRU</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cp0le2TusRU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Did Iguanas Get to Fiji?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/nS5320SueLE</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nS5320SueLE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 16:15:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[*****
PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to http://to.pbs.org/DonateEons
*****

Eons is a production of Complexly for PBS Digital Studios.

Super special thanks to the following Patreon patrons for helping make Eons possible:
rene fuqua, Casey Hague, Kerry Conneely, Susan Freund, Nicholas Arger, William Sunderland, Josh L, Beth K, Lea Nisay, Eric Younge, Beth-Ann Cheney, Elyssa, John D Elias, Ashley Glenn, Annemiek Arkema, Willie, Eric Edwards, Wookiee Henderson, SKS PHD, IAmHere, Nquiztor, lyric1981, Jennifer Courtemanche, Steve Hill, Eric Franklin, raus, Sarah Grunow-Mau, Randall George, Lance , Walter Ray-Dulany, Ruth Orr, Deanna Hernandez, Lianne Lairmore, John Celio, Kevin Lacson, Aaditya Mehta, Christopher Samuel, Collin Dutrow, Travis Bauer, Steven Kern, AllPizzasArePersonal, John H. Austin, Jr., Alex Hackman, Stephen Patterson, Gizmo, Karen Farrell, Mary Tevington, Irene Wood, Jason Rostoker, Jonathan Rust, Derek Helling, CalamityBangs, Brian Clubb, Mark Talbott-Williams, Nomi Alchin, Duane Westhoff, Albert Folsom, Dan Caffee, A.B. Heckert, Hillary Ryde-Collins, Yu Mei, Stephanie Schlea, Nick Ryhajlo, Betsy Radley, Jeff Graham, Nathan Paskett

If you'd like to support the channel, head over to http://patreon.com/eons and pledge for some cool rewards!

Want to follow Eons elsewhere on the internet?
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/eonsshow
Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/eonsshow/
Bluesky - https://bsky.app/profile/pbseons.bsky.social
#Eons

References:]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Robin Arzón Still Believes in Peloton</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/9rF-lVpNFw4</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9rF-lVpNFw4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Peloton has struggled with persistent sales declines since the pandemic, but Robin Arzón tells Jason Kelly why she still believes in the company’s mission.
 
Watch the full episode of The Deal on the Bloomberg app or listen wherever you get your podcasts.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>India at a crossroads - 100 years of the Hindu nationalist RSS movement | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dz9X4rlT_c</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6Dz9X4rlT_c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[India’s identity is shifting, with the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh reshaping the nation. As the Hindu nationalist RSS movement marks its centenary, DW explores how it’s become one of India’s most influential and controversial organizations.

India is at a crossroads. Gandhi’s vision of secularism, once central to the republic’s identity, is increasingly challenged by religion-based nationalism. At the heart of this shift is the Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh (RSS) — a large network with millions of followers. The RSS presents itself as the guardian of Hindu values, while critics widely classify it as a paramilitary organization. Under Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who has deep roots in the RSS, its influence reaches to the highest levels of political power. 
 
The documentary follows families, activists, and eyewitnesses who have been profoundly influenced by the RSS across generations, as well as those negatively impacted by its ideology. It reveals how the RSS, through discipline, rituals, and targeted youth training, is moulding a new generation for whom "Hindutva" — the idea of a Hindu nation — is becoming a lived reality. At the same time, religious minorities and interfaith couples face increasing social pressures and uncertainty.  

Founded in 1925 by K. B. Hedgewar, the early ideological figures of the RSS — most notably M. S. Golwalkar — engaged with European nationalist thinking at a time when fascist regimes were gaining ground. While they did not adopt these ideologies wholesale, aspects of the organizational models employed by Mussolini and Hitler appear to have informed the movement’s structure and strategies. 

As the RSS marks its 100th anniversary, its enduring and growing influence raises pressing questions: What remains of Gandhi’s vision for a pluralistic India? Where is the country heading?  And who does India belong to?

Through historical insight, personal narratives, and exclusive interviews, the film traces a nation at a crossroads — between tradition and modernity, inclusion and exclusion. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #india #rss 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We&apos;ve Finally Seen Jupiter&apos;s Core | Juno Year 8 Update II</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iTHApjlyVa0</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iTHApjlyVa0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 15:01:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Juno has finally seen Jupiter’s core, and it’s not what we expected.
Check out Astrum’s posters of Jupiter on Displate: https://astrumspace.info/Displates    

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Forget everything you thought you knew about Jupiter's core. Scientists long debated whether our solar system's largest planet had a dense, solid heart, or no core at all. But now, data from NASA’s Juno probe has revealed an answer no one expected: the core is ‘fuzzy’. This massive discovery completely upends all our current theories on how Jupiter, and every other gas giant, formed and evolved. Join us as we explore the data that changed everything. 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 What’s Inside Jupiter’s Core?
1:08 Core Theories
3:52 Juno’s Unexpected Discovery
7:32 How Did Jupiter Form? 
9:33 Saturn’s Core
13:03 Jupiter’s Magnetic Field 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum's newsletter has launched! Want to know what's happening in space? 
Sign up here: https://astrumspace.kit.com 

▀▀▀▀▀▀
 
Astrum Infographic Artwork: https://electrify.art/collections/astrum  
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/ 

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here to support the channel: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/6jPRrbq3o3dpvBb173ZTKi?si=a90d3efe3b704c83 

Astrum Earth: https://youtube.com/@AstrumEarth 
Astrum Extra: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumextra 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

References:
“Jupiter facts: structure and composition”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/jupiterfacts 
“Gravitational collapse theory of Jupiter’s formation”, via sciencedirect.com https://astrumspace.info/gravcollapse 
“Jupiter’s interior structure”, via missionjuno.swri.edu https://astrumspace.info/jupiterinterior 
“Jupiter’s dilute core from Juno data”, via sciencedirect.com https://astrumspace.info/dilutecore 
“Mystery of Jupiter’s strange core explained”, via sciencealert.com  https://astrumspace.info/jupiterstrangecore 
“New insights into Jupiter’s interior from Juno gravity data”, via mnras.oxfordjournals.org https://astrumspace.info/junogravity 
“Saturn ring seismology”, via sciencedirect.com https://astrumspace.info/saturnvibrations
“Hybrid equation of state models for Jupiter”, via arxiv.org https://astrumspace.info/jupitereos 
“Dynamo Simulations of Jupiter's Magnetic Field”, via agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com https://astrumspace.info/jupitermagfield 
“Juno and Jupiter science”, via issibern.ch https://astrumspace.info/junojupiter 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits:
Writer: Julia Masselos
Video Editor: Nick Shishkin
Researcher: Shourya Shrivastava
Script Editor: Damaris McColgan
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Channel Manager: Georgina Brenner
Production Manager: Raquel Taylor
Head of Astrum: Jess Jordan
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#Astrum #Space #Jupiter #Juno]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why do smartphones need multiple cameras? - Rachel Yang</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dm2AsJ3-E8</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7dm2AsJ3-E8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Learn more at https://brilliant.org/TedEd

--

When the Visualphone VP210 hit the market in 1999, it advertised a never-before-seen feature: a camera. With only .11 megapixels, the Visualphone is a relic compared to modern devices. But while this technology has improved dramatically, engineers are rapidly approaching a hard limit on phone camera quality. So, what's limiting them? Rachel Yang shares a snapshot of how digital cameras work.

Lesson by Rachel Yang, directed by Vicente Numpaque, Hernando Bahamon, Globizco Studios.

This video made possible in collaboration with Brilliant
Learn more about how TED-Ed partnerships work: https://bit.ly/TEDEdPartner

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/why-do-smartphones-need-multiple-cameras-rachel-yang
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/why-do-smartphones-need-multiple-cameras-rachel-yang/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.globizcostudios.com
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Michel-Ange Hortegat, Enes Kirimi, Amaury BISIAUX, ND, Samyogita Hardikar, Vanessa Graulich, Vandana Gunwani, Abdulmohsin Almadi, AJ Lyon, Geoffrey Bultitude, Mi Mi, Thomas Rothert, Brian Elieson, Oge O, Weronika Falkowska, Nevin Spoljaric, Sid Chanpuriya, Anoop Varghese, David Yastremski, Noah Webb, Roberto Chena, Oliver Koo, Luke Pisano, Andrea Gordon, Aleksandar Donev, Nicole Klau Ibarra, Jesse Lira, Ezekiel Raui, Petr Vacek, Dennis, Olivia Fu, Kari Teffeau, Cindy Lai, Rajath Durgada Manjunath, Dan Nguyen, Chin Beng Tan, Tom Boman, Karen Warner, Iryna Panasiuk, Aaron Torres, Eric Braun, Sonja Worzewski, Michael Clement, Adam Berry, Ghaith Tarawneh, Nathan Milford, Tomas Beckett, Alice Ice, Eric Berman, and Kurt Paolo Sevillano.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Lost in Chopin? The Opus Index is your musical GPS! 🎹🔍</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/EjNPgtsayvg</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EjNPgtsayvg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 14:09:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[🏆 Your Chopin Competition Companion: The Chopin Podcast Opus Index 🎶

The Chopin Podcast journey doesn’t end with the final episode! 🎉 We’ve created a complete Chopin Opus Index—A complete catalog of Chopin’s works, linked to the exact episode and timestamp we discussed them at during the podcast. 📚

https://patreon.com/BenLaude
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Bottle a Star</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/mxG0ts7qmq0</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mxG0ts7qmq0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 14:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Sun gives us endless energy... we only have to figure out how to store it. From mirrors and molten salt to ammonia fuel, here’s how we can bottle star power for later.

Creation supported by AHA – The Science Communication Hub and the Science Year 2025 – Energy of the Future

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science #renewableenergy

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ivan the Terrible and his Son Ivan by Ilya Repin: Great Art Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YXOlTjObWTw</link><author>Great Art Explained</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YXOlTjObWTw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 13:01:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCePDFpCr78_qmVtpoB1Axaw">Great Art Explained</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[My book Great Art Explained is ready to pre-order now worldwide 
My other channel, Great Books Explained here - https://www.youtube.com/@greatbooksexplained371 
Please consider supporting this channel on Patreon (and getting exclusive and uncensored content), thanks! https://www.patreon.com/user?u=53686503 
or if you prefer a one-off donation - https://paypal.me/GreatArtExplained?country.x=GB&locale.x=en_GB 
Alternatively, every video has a "thanks" button under it- I appreciate it! 

Ilya Repin's Ivan the Terrible and his Son Ivan, is one of the most controversial and shocking images in Russian art. 
When it was unveiled in 1885, it caused such a scandal that the Tsar himself banned it from public view.
Since then, it has been physically attacked twice - slashed in 1913 and nearly destroyed again in 2018. To this day, Russian nationalists denounce it, insisting it is Western propaganda, historically inaccurate, and unfair to Ivan the Terrible.
But the painting leaves little room for doubt. Here, Ivan the Terrible - Russia’s first crowned Tsar - has just struck down his own son in a violent rage, moments after attacking his pregnant daughter-in-law and causing her to miscarry.
This isn’t simply a historical scene. It is a universal story of rage, regret, domination, and destruction - an image that still reverberates through time. And is still relevant. 

IMPORTANT!  
Subscribe and click the bell icon to be notified! https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCePD... 

I would like to thank all my Patreon supporters, in particular Alan Stewart, Alexander Velser, AMSN, Andrei Surei, Anja Zeutschel, Bria Nicole Art, Brian J Rich, David Asabreu, Ed Gobbi, "Elias', Eric Mann, Francis Song, Griffin Evans, Jemma Theivendran, Joe Kool, Jon Hanzen, Julio Cardenas, Kibibi Shaw, Louise Tait, Matthew Bondaryk, Mitch Kosowski, Monte St Johns, New Curiosity, Paul Ark, Paul Waterman, Daniel Rakovski, Sam Blakelock, Sean Welgemoed, Stephen Beresford, Tanya Moore, Theresa Garfink, and Toni Ko. 


"What a brilliant series this is" - Stephen Fry on Twitter (X) 

CREDITS 
Script co-written by Laura Beardsell-Moore 
Opening 
Animation and Title Sequence by Brian Adsit (instagram https://instagram.com/brian_vfx?utm_m... and Behance www.behance.com/badsit88) 
Recording by Robert Lewis 

VIDEOS 
All the videos, songs, images, and graphics used in the video belong to their respective owners and I or this channel do not claim any right over them. 

MUSIC 
Prokofiev Toccata D minor, op 11
Prokofiev Romeo and Juliet Dance of the Knights 

BOOKS 
The Russian Vision: The Art of Ilya Repin by David Jackson 
Ilya Repin (Great Painters) by G.IU. Sternin and Yelena Kirillina
Ilya REPIN: The Russian Soul on Canvas (Russian Painting from the Romanovs to Stalin) by Grigori Sternin

Copyright Disclaimer under section 107 of the Copyright Act of 1976, allowance is made for “fair use” for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, education and research. Fair use is a use permitted by copyright statute that might otherwise be infringing.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Learning Python Programming • Fabrizio Romano &amp; Naomi Ceder • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yi-Kv882umU</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Yi-Kv882umU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 12:01:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club. #GOTOcon #GOTObookclub
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Read the full transcription of the interview here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/401

Fabrizio Romano - Development Manager at Sohonet & Co-Author of "Learning Python Programming"
Naomi Ceder - Python Instruction and Consulting & Author of "The Quick Python Book" @NaomiCeder 

RESOURCES
Fabrizio
https://x.com/gianchub
https://github.com/gianchub
https://www.linkedin.com/in/gianchub

Naomi
https://bsky.app/profile/naomiceder.tech
https://github.com/nceder
https://www.linkedin.com/in/naomiceder
https://www.naomiceder.tech

Links
https://adventofcode.com
https://youtu.be/7CwmUmQjvYg
https://youtu.be/qmh7Uppd3x0
https://youtu.be/ahyF8e9qKBc
https://youtu.be/SYrVZR_g718
https://youtu.be/lWPLgm52ICs
https://youtu.be/EFXxXFHpS0M
https://youtu.be/Xqnv1vzB9lc
https://youtu.be/IX3300umebg
https://youtu.be/ul5vjXTNSsE
https://youtu.be/Pv0cfsastFs
https://youtu.be/MNRIJsoi-Ds
https://youtu.be/pzlqeX9nh1g

DESCRIPTION
Naomi Ceder interviews Fabrizio Romano, author of "Learning Python Programming" (now in its 4th edition). They discuss Fabrizio’s decade-long journey as a Python programmer and book author, exploring how his perspectives have evolved across multiple editions.

Key topics include the shift from GUI-focused content to command-line applications, the controversial introduction of typing in Python, the rise of AI in coding, and the importance of educating junior developers. Fabrizio emphasizes the balance between embracing new tools like AI while maintaining fundamental programming skills and the human element in software development.

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
01:49 The journey of writing 4 book editions
04:48 From scripts to command-line interfaces (CLI)
11:51 Adding a collaborator
14:38 The evolution of Python typing
18:33 Coding challenges as a passion project
22:20 AI & the future of coding
29:34 Outro

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Fabrizio Romano & Heinrich Kruger • Learning Python Programming • https://amzn.to/4myLBIt
Naomi Ceder • The Quick Python Book • https://amzn.to/3zwdDOa
Luciano Ramalho • Fluent Python • https://amzn.to/3oSw2je
David Beazley • Python Distilled (Developer's Library) • https://amzn.to/3QjNBEv
Anna Skoulikari • Learning Git • https://amzn.to/4cSl8lz
Sy Brand • Building a Debugger • https://amzn.to/4cWWr84

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Python #Python3 #LearningPythonProgramming #Coding #PythonTutorial #FluentPython #PythonDistilled #AISolutions #AdventOfCode #CommandLine #CommandLineInterfaces #CLI #SoftwareEngineering #Programming #TodayInTech #FabrizioRomano #NaomiCeder #BookClub

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why pilots LOVED the Vulcan Bomber</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/FmstNYkOMNI</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FmstNYkOMNI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#vulcan #vulcanbomber #history #coldwar #raf #pilot #historyfacts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unboxing Gateron Lanes switches!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R3i1G_B5yVA</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/R3i1G_B5yVA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 05:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Chyrosran22</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get them here: https://pantheonkeys.com/products/gateron-lanes-tactile-switches
Today, a short unboxing of something that's been highly requested; Gateron Lanes switches! These are tactile versions of Gateron Melodic; Alps-inspired tactile switches with a leaf spring in them. Currently they appear to be gone out of stock everywhere but hopefully there'll be more soon!

Intro by Kyle Carter
Outro by Facundo Cabanne

My keyboard reviews: http://bit.ly/1TbOtft
My switch teardowns: http://bit.ly/2C1QGHz
My TOP X videos: http://bit.ly/2FmpZfd
My XL typing demos: https://bit.ly/2OoAW3w
My tutorials and featurettes: https://bit.ly/2OrkLUh
My unboxing videos: https://bit.ly/2TSrr0m

I'm Thomas and I do videos and reviews on mechanical keyboards ranging from the most sickening modern RGB gaming keyboards to vintage hardware relics, or sometimes keycaps or keyswitches ranging from Cherry MX to Alps SKCM to IBM buckling springs and anything in between.

Follow me on Twitter for updates on my keyboard videos! https://twitter.com/chyrosran22]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Emanuel Ax on Chopin&apos;s Chamber Music (Cello Sonata, Piano Trio, Polonaise Brillante)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sHtT87aFx6w</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sHtT87aFx6w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 2 Oct 2025 03:45:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[OPUS INDEX: https://index.chopinpodcast.com
MERCH: https://www.chopinpodcast.com/merch

Season 2 Episode 7 Variety Show: FULL AUDIO COMING SOON

0:00 Violinists can’t keep their hands off Chopin
2:10 Playing Chopin is healthy for you
3:54 Piano Trio, Op. 8
11:09 Introduction and polonaise brillante, Op. 3
13:40 The Cello Sonata is a masterpiece
19:10 Friendship with Yo-Yo Ma
22:59 Fantasy on Polish Airs, Op. 13
25:20 Nationalism vs universality in music
30:33 Garrick Ohlsson for President

Chopin: Chamber Music (Ax, Ma, Frank): https://open.spotify.com/album/7mSGdugkBh5Aaxg1kn3WlF?si=_x5nNXTlQWOphWFL0KmWVQ

This podcast is produced in partnership with the Chopin Foundation of the United States, which presents the National Chopin Competition every 5 years. For more, visit https://chopin.org

The Chopin Foundation is a national non-profit organization founded by its President, Blanka A. Rosenstiel in 1977, and inspired by the first US Chopin Competition she presented in Miami in 1975. Support the Chopin Foundation: https://chopin.org/donate

Access bonus scenes from interviews with Emanuel Ax and other guests:
https://patreon.com/BenLaude

https://www.facebook.com/chopinpodcast
https://www.facebook.com/benlawdy
https://www.instagram.com/benlawdy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nevada is home to more than 600 ghost towns #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/32Cp6UJglsI</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/32Cp6UJglsI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 23:18:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Vox producer Dolly Li road tripped through northern Nevada to try and find some of these hidden ghost towns and learn about the real history behind the boom and bust cycles of mining in the state. Along the way, she stops by a town that many call a ghost town, but is still home to a dozen residents.

Through visiting a few abandoned places and speaking to historians about the technology and infrastructure that made mining a key industry of the state, we piece together a rich and fascinating story of Nevada’s development. #nevada #ghost #ghosttowns

This video is presented by Travel Nevada. Travel Nevada doesn’t have a say in our editorial decisions, but they make videos (and adventures!) like this one possible.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pete Buttigieg on the ‘T’ Being Removed from LGBT</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/k5PiKccGvIg</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/k5PiKccGvIg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 22:41:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Father Cares for His Ill Son | Caregiving</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=90RFQLTwXSw</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/90RFQLTwXSw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 22:00:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch more: https://to.pbs.org/45m7zcL | #CaregivingPBS
Greg and CoRy share a deep bond built on love, creativity, and care. When CoRy’s chronic illnesses made living alone impossible, he moved in with his father, Greg. His father devoted himself to caring for him, but as time passes, CoRy realizes he will one day need to care for his father too. Lean on Me is a tender portrait of a loving father-son relationship.

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS app: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#fatherhood #caregiver #caregiversupport 

Support for Caregiving is made possible by Otsuka America Pharmaceutical Inc.; Comfort Keepers; CareScout Holdings, Inc.; Care.com; Evelyn Y. Davis Foundation; Richard King Mellon Foundation; The Arthur Vining Davis Foundations; Ford Foundation; Ralph C. Wilson, Jr. Foundation; NextFifty Initiative (Next50); National Alliance on Mental Illness (NAMI); PATH Foundation; Care for All with Respect and Equity (CARE) Fund; The John A. Hartford Foundation; and the Corporation for Public Broadcasting. 

Caregiving is a production of Lea Pictures and @WETANationalProductions Washington, D.C., in association with Ark Media. For Ark Media, Chris Durrance serves as Director and Senior Producer; Barak Goodman is Series Producer; and Ruth Fertig is Producer. Executive Producers for Lea Pictures are Bradley Cooper and Weston Middleton. Executive Producers for WETA are John F. Wilson and Tom Chiodo. Producer for WETA is Kate Kelly. Production is managed for WETA by Jim Corbley. Consulting Producer is Paul Irving.

National outreach and engagement partners for Caregiving include Rosalynn Carter Institute for Caregivers; Grantmakers In Aging; Milken Institute | Future of Aging; Global Coalition on Aging; Wallis Annenberg GenSpace; Elizabeth Dole Foundation; National Partnership for Healthcare and Hospice Innovation; National Minority Health Association; Fred Rogers Productions; Caregiver Action Network; The Coalition to Transform Advanced Care; American Association of Caregiving Youth; Caring Across Generations; SHRM and SHRM Foundation; National Alliance for Caregiving; Lutheran Services in America; Center to Advance Palliative Care; PEOPLE; and Forbes.com. 

A production of Lea Pictures and WETA Washington, D.C., In association with Ark Media. © Copyright 2024, WETA Washington, D.C., Lea Pictures and Ark Media. All Rights Reserved.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gallic Wars: The Celts And Romans Bloody Battle For Europe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pwL4q_8cd1E</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pwL4q_8cd1E?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 21:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Join experts as they uncover the unknown history of the Celts, a people who left no written record but communicated their past through song and story. In this episode, explore the history of the Celts from their rise as a dominant culture in Iron Age Europe to their eventual decline and assimilation into the Roman Empire. And join experts as they explore why the Celts moved from prosperous cities into smaller fortified settlements and how this triggered their decline in Central Europe.  

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.
Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://bit.ly/4pyExyn

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Sen. Elizabeth Warren says the government shutdown is all about health care #shutdown #government</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/xeW1904X5Fc</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xeW1904X5Fc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 19:41:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Democratic Sen. Elizabeth Warren speaks with Today, Explained co-host Sean Rameswaram about the government shutdown and what it means for Americans’ health care coverage.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pete Buttigieg responds to Tucker Carlson “fake gay” claims</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/d4NOTAu48Y0</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/d4NOTAu48Y0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 18:22:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Deep Beauty of Our Solar System | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iKmYgSAbVYU</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iKmYgSAbVYU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sit back, relax and enjoy  a 1 hour deep dive into the wonders of our splendacious solar system.

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from 'Solar System' (2024) Where Professor Brian Cox explores our solar system to reveal the strange worlds visible to us as never before.

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Biggest Mystery in the Universe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/GpRyLI5I3iI</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GpRyLI5I3iI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 18:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Letters from a Chechen prison - Zarema and her rebel family | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tABNa8WG6VA</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tABNa8WG6VA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 16:01:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The story of Zarema, kidnapped and imprisoned in Chechnya for defending human rights. Nine years in a penal colony: That is the sentence Zarema Musayeva has to serve because her sons rebelled against Chechen ruler Ramzan Kadyrov. Zarema’s family is doing everything they can to ensure she is not forgotten.

Every dictator has their own way of intimidating opponents. In Chechnya, Ramzan Kadyrov punishes human rights activists by imprisoning someone close to them. Abubakar, Ibragim and Baisangur Yangulbayev are vocal critics of Ramzan Kadyrov. They denounce abuses in Chechnya on the internet and were forced to flee Russia. Their mother Zarema Musayeva was less fortunate. In January 2022, authorities abducted her from her home in Nizhny Novgorod, some 1,800 kilometers from the Chechen capital Grozny. Her health has deteriorated significantly since then. She suffers from diabetes but is forced to do hard labor. Zarema is paying a high price for the commitment of her sons, who are continuing their actions in exile in the hope that international attention will save their mother's life. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #kadyrov #chechnya #humanrights 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Edgar Allan Poe&apos;s Encounter With an Evil Spirit</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/f1XtuQYCKWE</link><author>Horses</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f1XtuQYCKWE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 16:01:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrx2zrPjhGRi9TwszZiLwEg">Horses</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find the full, uncensored version of this essay and more at: ⁠https://horses.land]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Key to Building Strong Teams</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/VJkcYVRmQHw</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VJkcYVRmQHw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Robin Arzón explains to Alex Rodriguez why storytelling, rituals and connecting with fandom are essential for building strong teams.

Watch the full episode of The Deal on the Bloomberg app or listen wherever you get your podcasts.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pete Buttigieg Interview</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DlL376A1hMo</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DlL376A1hMo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 15:25:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Use code channel5 at https://incogni.com/channel5 to get an exclusive 60% off.

00:00:00 – Opening
00:01:06 – Concerns and Opportunities around AI
00:04:18 – AI's Impact on Unemployment
00:06:11 – Tucker Carlson’s "Fake Gay" Accusation
00:09:08 – Reactions to Coming Out
00:12:02 – Homophobia and Removing the 'T' from LGBTQ
00:13:32 – Growing up Liberal in a Conservative State
00:14:35 – New York City Mayoral Race and Youth Political Engagement
00:17:32 – Policy Solutions for Cost of Living
00:24:18 – Skepticism around Socialism
00:27:28 – Israel/Palestine Conflict: Pete’s Take
00:32:27 – Anti-Semitism in the US Post-10/7
00:38:14 – Trump and American Interventionism
00:41:04 – Change in Attitudes toward Military Service
00:50:20 – Reflections on Afghanistan Withdrawal
00:54:05 – Pete's Future: Presidential Aspirations and Progressive Leadership
00:56:01 – Urban Governance: Housing, Policing, and Compassion in Cities
00:59:04 – Highs and Lows of the Airline Industry 
01:02:49 – East Palestine Derailment
01:07:40 – Urban Design: Walkability, Sprawl, Culture of Transit
01:09:48 – Indiana: Revitalizing Gary, Indiana via Transit and Environmental Recovery
01:11:00 – Pete’s Maltese heritage, Irish Inventions, Peace in Northern Ireland]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Exclusive Hands-On with the New FN Evolys: Live Fire &amp; Full Breakdown with expert Jonathan Ferguson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KRqJFsEK4t0</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KRqJFsEK4t0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 15:15:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Step into the future of firepower.

In this exclusive hands-on, Jonathan takes a deep dive into FN Herstal’s Evolys: the next-gen machine gun bridging the gap between assault rifle and light machine gun.

0:00 Intro 
1:27 Origins & Development 
3:20 Specs 
5:40 Key Design Features
17:54 Range Demo
21:47 Future & Outro

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ChatGPT vs Brain Shocking Study Results!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/PgJmhuEAPmk</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PgJmhuEAPmk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Preserving Maya knowledge in the forests of Belize | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/v8ZTH8RtRgI</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/v8ZTH8RtRgI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[There are tens of thousands of Maya descendants in Belize. Maria Garcia is one of them. She is a healer who is preserving her ancestors’ knowledge of medicinal plants. But the forests and nature on which the Maya rely are under threat from logging and climate change. 

Maria Garcia founded an organization that protects 5,000 hectares of rainforest. Together with a group of rangers, the organization patrols the area to keep it safe.  

“The rangers are the soul of this park. They are the ones who take care of everything – from the logging to the looting, to the hunting. When you know the struggle [...] then you know how important this area is and you will fight for it with all your heart. It’s not about the money. It’s about preserving the balance that we have. Because our sacred lands are fast disappearing,” says Maria. 
 
Watch the full documentary “The Maya of Belize - The battle for culture, the rainforest and ancient knowledge” on the DW Documentary YouTube channel. 
 
#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #Maya #Belize #inspirationalquotes 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Genius Idea That Won The Battle Of Britain</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0yHHKADmgsM</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0yHHKADmgsM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 13:01:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Battle of Britain showcased not only the bravery of pilots but also the importance of coordination, intelligence, and infrastructure behind the scenes. But how did Britain organise such a strategic success? And what part did Duxford’s Operations Block play in defending the British Isles?

Join IWM Duxford tour guide John Lewis as he takes us inside the historic Operations Room: the nerve centre that played a crucial role in stopping Hitler’s aerial invasion of Britain.

Plan your visit to IWM Duxford: https://www.iwm.org.uk/visits/iwmduxford

Explore and licence the film clips used in this video from IWM Film:
https://film.iwmcollections.org.uk/collections/_3aPnPd9g

Follow IWM on social media: 
x.com/I_W_M 
instagram.com/imperialwarmuseums 
facebook.com/iwm.london 
tiktok.com/@imperialwarmuseums

#history #ww2 #battleofbritain]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Future of Serverless • Nick Coult • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5sZR5X7noi0</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5sZR5X7noi0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at GOTO Serverless 2025. #GOTOcon #GOTOserverless
https://conferences.gotopia.tech/goto-serverless-bengaluru-2025

Nick Coult - Director of Product for Serverless at AWS 

RESOURCES
https://x.com/nickcoult
https://github.com/coultn
https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickcoult

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
02:48 What is serverless?
04:35 Why serverless?
06:32 Pioneering serverless compute
08:25 Event-driven architectures
13:13 AI agents
14:51 Agentic or serverless?
22:06 What are we doing to help build for the future?
26:26 Start now
27:32 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://conferences.gotopia.tech/goto-serverless-bengaluru-2025/sessions/3848

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Peter Sbarski • Serverless Architectures on AWS • https://amzn.to/3hJzEUM
Michael Stack • Event-Driven Architecture in Golang • https://amzn.to/3G5e8ST
Ashley Peacock • Serverless Apps on Cloudflare • https://amzn.to/3EU7P85
Jeroen Mulder • Multi-Cloud Strategy for Cloud Architects • https://amzn.to/3FdNDOA

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Serverless #AWSServerless #FutureOfServerless #EDA #EventDrivenArchitecture #NickCoult

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kate Liu Reacts to Her Chopin Performance that Inspired a Generation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O4xn6YqRXkY</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/O4xn6YqRXkY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 1 Oct 2025 02:18:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch Kate Liu's performance: https://www.youtube.com/@chopininstitute  

OPUS INDEX: https://index.chopinpodcast.com
MERCH: https://www.chopinpodcast.com/merch

Season 2 Episode 7 Variety Show: FULL AUDIO COMING SOON

0:00 A Chopin performance that has has touched millions
2:20 Kate listens to her Andante spianato
5:14 How Kate achieves a pearly sound
9:03 Reading the comments about Kate's performance
12:32 Kate listens to her Grande Polonaise
16:14 Feeling the dance, interpreting the scene change
20:36 One example of her brilliance
23:48 The drive for perfection

Check out Kate's new album: https://www.orchidclassics.com/releases/orc100359-kate-liu/

This podcast is produced in partnership with the Chopin Foundation of the United States, which presents the National Chopin Competition every 5 years. For more, visit https://chopin.org

The Chopin Foundation is a national non-profit organization founded by its President, Blanka A. Rosenstiel in 1977, and inspired by the first US Chopin Competition she presented in Miami in 1975. Support the Chopin Foundation: https://chopin.org/donate

Access bonus scenes from interviews with Kate Liu and other guests:
https://patreon.com/BenLaude

https://www.facebook.com/chopinpodcast
https://www.facebook.com/benlawdy
https://www.instagram.com/benlawdy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The O.J. Verdict (full documentary) | Inside the Simpson Trial &amp; Its Impact on the U.S. | FRONTLINE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1W3BLcQGQQc</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1W3BLcQGQQc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 23:00:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">FRONTLINE PBS | Official</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ofra Bikel’s seminal 2005 documentary on the startling truths and lasting impact of the O.J. Simpson trial is now streaming on YouTube for the first time, marking the 30th anniversary of a verdict that shook the U.S.

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station here: 
https://www.pbs.org/donate 

It had been more than a year since proceedings in what was being called “the trial of the century” began, and America was on edge. Millions of households across the U.S. had tuned in to wall-to-wall coverage of onetime American icon O.J. Simpson’s trial for the brutal double murder of his ex-wife, Nicole Brown Simpson, and her friend Ron Goldman. 

Then, on Oct. 3, 1995, came a televised verdict, watched by more than 150 million people, that shook the country along racial lines — sparking both consternation and celebration, and raising profound questions about the criminal justice system, fairness and America’s racial divide.

Initially released 10 years after the not-guilty verdict was handed down, “The O.J. Verdict” was directed by Ofra Bikel, an award-winning FRONTLINE filmmaker whose body of work exposed flaws in the U.S. criminal justice system and helped bring about the exonerations of at least 13 people. 

Through extensive interviews with both the prosecution and defense teams, as well as journalists who covered the proceedings, this acclaimed documentary offers an in-depth look at how the trial played out and what it revealed about the nation.

Explore additional reporting on “The O.J. Verdict” on our website:
https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/oj/

#Documentary #OJSimpson #SimpsonTrial

Subscribe on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/user/PBSfrontline 
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/frontlinepbs​
Twitter: https://twitter.com/frontlinepbs​
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/frontline

FRONTLINE is produced at GBH in Boston and is broadcast nationwide on PBS. Funding for FRONTLINE is provided through the support of PBS viewers and by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting. Additional support for FRONTLINE is provided by the Abrams Foundation, Park Foundation, the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, and the FRONTLINE Journalism Fund, with major support from Jon and Jo Ann Hagler on behalf of the Jon L. Hagler Foundation, and additional support from Koo and Patricia Yuen, and Laura DeBonis and Scott Nathan.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Something Strange Happens When You Trace How Connected We Are</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CYlon2tvywA</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CYlon2tvywA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The beautiful math behind six degrees of separation. Sponsored by Incogni - use code veritasium at https://incogni.com/veritasium to get an exclusive 60% off.

If you’re looking for a molecular modelling kit, try Snatoms, a kit I invented where the atoms snap together magnetically - https://ve42.co/SnatomsV 

Sign up to the Veritasium newsletter for weekly science updates - https://ve42.co/Newsletter

To play around with the simulations in the video, you can follow these links:
Disease spreading - https://www.veritasium.com/simulation2
Preferential attachment - https://ve42.co/barabasiAlbertSim 


▀▀▀
A huge thank you to: 
Duncan Watts, for creating the small-world model that inspired this video and expanding on his further work; Steve Strogatz, for telling the story with such clarity & humour; Albert-László Barabási, for revealing the the inevitability and impact of hubs; Mark Buchanan, for his insightful takeaways that pulled it all together.

Check out Duncan Watts’ books here - https://www.amazon.com/Six-Degrees-Science-Connected-Age/dp/0393325423
Check out Mark Buchanan’s book here - https://ve42.co/bookNexusWorlds 

▀▀▀
Chapters:
0:00 What is six degrees of separation?
4:23 Network Shortcuts
7:11 The Strength of Weak Ties
8:20 Proving it’s a small world
10:39 How quickly can disease spread?
12:36 Strogatz goes viral
16:59 What is a network hub?
18:23 Preferential Attachment
23:38 The Prisoner’s Dilemma 
28:22 Your behavior can change the world’s


▀▀▀
References can be found here - https://ve42.co/networksRefs 

Image and video references can be found here - https://ve42.co/networksVisuals 

▀▀▀
Special thanks to our Patreon supporters:
Alex Porter, Alexander Tamas, Anton Ragin, Anupam Banerjee, Gnare, Ibby Hadeed, Jon Jamison, Juan Benet, Lee Redden, Meekay, Orlando Bassotto, Paul Peijzel, Richard Sundvall, Sam Lutfi, Ubiquity Ventures, Adam Foreman, Albert Wenger, armedtoe, Balkrishna Heroor, Bertrand Serlet, Blake Byers, Bruce, Dave Kircher, David Johnston, David Tseng, Evgeny Skvortsov, Garrett Mueller, gpoly, Jeromy Johnson, KeyWestr, Kyi, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Matthias Wrobel, meg noah, Michael Bush, Michael Krugman, Robert Oliveira, Tj Steyn & wolfee

▀▀▀
Writers: James Moore, Casper Mebius & Derek Muller
Producer & Director: James Moore 
Editors: Peter Nelson & Jack Saxon
Camera Operators: Derek Muller & Casper Mebius
Animators: Andrew Neet, Emma Wright, Fabio Albertelli & Ivy Tello
Illustrators: Jakub Misiek
Assistant Editor: James Stuart
Researchers: Callum Cuttle, Aakash Singh Bagga & Gabe Strong 
Simulations: Callum Cuttle, Gabe Strong & Ivy Tello
Sound Designers: Pavle Peric & James Stuart
Thumbnail Designers: Abdallah Rabah, Ren Hurley & Ben Powell
Production Team: Josh Pitt, Nicola Griffiths & Rob Beasley Spence
Executive Producers: Derek Muller & Casper Mebius
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images, Storyblocks
Music from Epidemic Sound]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rare Uncensored Footage From The Bloodiest Years Of The Cold War</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hYeh_4b-JLc</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hYeh_4b-JLc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:00:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This documentary explores the complex and often terrifying history of the Cold War, the decades-long standoff between the United States and the Soviet Union. Using rare archival footage and declassified documents, we delve into the world of espionage, nuclear brinkmanship, and global proxy wars that defined a generation. Discover the secret spies, controversial political figures, and covert operations that brought the world to the brink of nuclear war and reshaped modern history.

Do you love uncovering the past, exploring historic sites, and venturing to distant lands? Join History Hit today and stream hundreds of exclusive documentaries, with new releases every week. Plus, enjoy ad-free access to our podcast network for even more history every week.

Head over to https://bit.ly/45CPh5u to embark on your journey through history!

This channel is part of the Little Dot Studios Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What Caused the Downfall of Vice?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/JVs9Eby5byU</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JVs9Eby5byU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 20:59:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dynamic, dangerous and full of predators. YES #human #rainforest #anthropology</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/-abs_vrMOxs</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-abs_vrMOxs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Find out where to watch Human in your region 👉 https://www.bbcearth.com/shows/human

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>🎹 Chopin knew… B Major is comfier than C Major 😉</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/RJV8t0hZlzE</link><author>Ben Laude</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RJV8t0hZlzE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:14:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnSFlVqRyNfIJDsmpkcY57w">Ben Laude</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Chopin Competition jury member Garrick Ohlsson breaks down the thirteenth of 16 ways that Chopin revolutionized modern piano playing.

https://patreon.com/BenLaude/
https://instagram.com/benlawdy/
https://benlaude.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>James Webb Telescope Distance Determination Methods Explained!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/-geGHu29lBA</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-geGHu29lBA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>From Corporate Lawyer to Peloton Fitness Instructor</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/x00P-Wk6vaQ</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/x00P-Wk6vaQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:01:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Robin Arzón shares with Alex Rodriguez and Jason Kelly how she went from corporate law to becoming a Peloton fitness instructor and why she made the leap.

Watch the full episode of The Deal on the Bloomberg app or listen wherever you get your podcasts https://lnkd.in/exqzTyw5

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The San Andreas Fault - Is a huge earthquake looming in California?| DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vfIcDOfAR8</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7vfIcDOfAR8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[California is one of the most active earthquake regions in the world. The San Andreas Fault, a 1,300-kilometer-long fracture zone in the earth's crust, runs through the cities of San Francisco and Los Angeles. Scientists fear a major earthquake.

The San Andreas Fault is currently the most strongly observed geological phenomenon in the world. Scientists have long feared an earthquake so strong that it could mean the death of thousands of people. Economic damage, running into the billions, would also result. 

Concerns are growing, as seismologists currently estimate that the next earthquake will occur before 2032. They put the probability of this at over 70%. For them, it is a race against time. 

The documentary shows the scientific efforts being made to predict the unpredictable. International seismologists are studying the fault to make more accurate forecasts. The aim is also to reduce the risks for people. 

With the help of 3D animations and aerial photographs, the researchers' fascinating engineering approaches come to light. For them, the question is not whether the big quake will come, but when.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #earthquake #california #usa 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Debate Over The Age of the Universe, with Wendy Freedman</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93ddCCSsvOg</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/93ddCCSsvOg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:50:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Can we resolve the crisis in cosmology? Neil deGrasse Tyson and co-host Matt Kirshen take on Hubble Tension, the difference between the estimated ages of the universe, and how to solve it with legendary astronomer Wendy Freedman.

We trace the debate from the early days with Henrietta Leavitt’s discovery of Cepheid variables through today’s most precise measurements. Why do local distance measurements (Cepheids, tip of the red-giant branch, carbon stars) give a different expansion rate than the cosmic microwave background? Could dust be dimming our view, or systematic errors biasing our results? Or do we require discovering new physics?

We break down the Hubble tension and what caused it. How did the Hubble telescope complicate the existing debate, between 10 and 20 billion years old, through more precise measurements? We explore possible explanations: local density fluctuations, evolving dark energy, or something missing from the standard model. Are we missing something fundamental hiding in plain sight? Could the Hubble constant vary with time, or even by location in the universe?

Listener questions push the frontier further: Could dark energy distort our distance calculations? How would we measure expansion if we traveled to another galaxy? Would it matter scientifically, or emotionally, if the universe is finite or infinite? Through it all, Neil reminds us that science isn’t democracy, it’s data.

Thanks to our Patrons Smallevent, Ralph, Arun, Pandey, Nick Ohlheiser, Dantheman, Brian Campana, Mel, Micheal TRilling, Daniel Arvizu, James, Lily Morant, Jon Githrex, Daniel Frank, Gini Kramer, Opal Lehman, M M, pheobekate, Najwa DeForest, Kyle, Mama M, Jerome Cameron, Charles, David "Kiwi" Keller, Scott Chaddon, Erin T, Quin Shimamura, Wilma, Jerry the Epicurean, Matt Brady, loreen spchler, AlexK89, Eric Lee, Mantautas Jokubenas, Dustin, Regina Rhew Hoilman, Professional Dave, Nicholas Hayes, Joe White, Eddie Olsson, Amanda Granberry, Gloria Askin, Crimson Blaze, Steven Banker, Chris Washington, Ethan, oliver cooke, Terrence Sauvain, Maurice van der Linden, Yesking, joe vaughn, Micheal Wilson, Daaku, Espen Sande Larsen, Deepanshu Biniwale, Alexis Barrera, Kalie Pillar, ConcernedOnlooker, Margaret, Vinay Murthy, Finesse TheGod, Fraser PArk Vlad, AdamJ, Alexander Verharen, Susan Soard, Pete, Jaidyn Janis, Joe, AndyL, and Paul Williams for supporting us this week.

Timestamps:
00:00 Introduction: Wendy Freedman
08:10 - What’s Hubble Tension?
15:32 - Cracks in Our Theories & Uncertainties
21:24 - Solving the Crisis
29:37 - Precision v. Accuracy
33:44 - Does the Hubble Constant Change? 
39:50 - Is Dark Energy Messing With Us? 
41:38 - Scrapping the Standard Model? 
42:59 - Interstellar Travel & Expansion
45:46 - Infinite or Finite Universe

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Finally Know What the Surface of Venus Looks Like</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZJfHBc4-0w</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XZJfHBc4-0w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:00:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In this Supercut, we’re exploring our deadly neighbour: Venus
Go to http://buyraycon.com/astrumopen to get 20% off sitewide!

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Meet Venus: our most lethal planetary neighbour. Cloaked entirely in reflective, sulfuric acid clouds, it has evaded many attempts to observe its inner workings by obliterating any visitor to its surface. Through incredible feats of engineering, from the Soviet Venera landers to NASA's Magellan mission, we've finally unveiled its true face of sprawling volcanoes and fractured plains. Join us in this supercut as we explore the planet that no human could survive, and find out what its extreme environment can teach us about Earth.

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 Venus, Our Neighbour
1:16 What You Need to Know About Venus
6:14 Why Venera Went Silent on Venus
21:37 Venera's Venus Images Have Nothing On Magellan
36:39 Future Missions

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum's newsletter has launched! Want to know what's happening in space? 
Sign up here: https://astrumspace.kit.com 

▀▀▀▀▀▀
 
Astrum Displate Posters: https://astrumspace.info/Displates 
Astrum Infographic Artwork: https://electrify.art/collections/astrum  
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/ 

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here to support the channel: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/6jPRrbq3o3dpvBb173ZTKi?si=a90d3efe3b704c83 

Astrum Earth: https://youtube.com/@AstrumEarth 
Astrum Extra: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumextra 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

References:
“Venus”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/venusinfo   
“Magellan”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/magellan
“Venus facts”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/venusfacts 
“Venus: thick atmosphere and runaway greenhouse effect”, via nature.com https://astrumspace.info/venusgreenhouse
“The atmosphere of Venus: composition, structure, and dynamics”, via springer.com https://astrumspace.info/venusatmosphere
“Data Base of Impact Craters on Venus”, via usgs.gov https://astrumspace.info/venuscraters
“The Surface of Venus”, via oxfordre.com https://astrumspace.info/venussurface
“Ongoing Venus Volcanic Activity Discovered With Magellan Data”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/volcanicactivity
“Coronae formation on Venus”, via wiley.com https://astrumspace.info/venuscoronae
“NASA Selects 2 Missions to Study ‘Lost Habitable’ World of Venus”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/futuremissions

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits:
Writers: Jon McColgan, Ross McDonald, Julia Masselos
Video Editors: Nathália Huzian, Nick Shishkin
Researcher: Shourya Shrivastava
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Channel Manager: Georgina Brenner
Production Manager: Raquel Taylor
Head of Astrum: Jess Jordan
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#Astrum #Space #Venus]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Greek myth of the Fates’ prophecy - Iseult Gillespie</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B-ukcWJzXwc</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/B-ukcWJzXwc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the Greek myth of Meleager, who set out to end a boar’s destruction of his city along with Greece’s best warriors.

--

The night of her son's birth, the queen of Calydon was visited by three shadowy goddesses, known as the Fates. They gestured towards the blazing hearth and decreed that her son would live only until the burning log was reduced to embers. Terrified, the queen locked the log in a chest and guarded the key— but the secret would loom over his life. Iseult Gillespie shares the Greek myth of Meleager.

Lesson by Iseult Gillespie, directed by Layron DeJarnette, Gumboyo Animation.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-greek-myth-of-the-fates-prophecy-iseult-gillespie
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-greek-myth-of-the-fates-prophecy-iseult-gillespie/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.gumboyo.com
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Jennifer Heald, Megulo Abebe, isolwi, Kate Sem, Ujjwal Dasu, Angel Alberici, Minh Quan Dinh, Sylvain, Terran Gimpel, Talia Sari, Katie McDowell, Allen, Mahina Knuckles, Charmaine Hanson, Thawsitt, Jezabel, Abdullah Abdulaziz, Xiao Yu, Melissa Suarez, Brian A. Dunn, Francisco Amaya, Daisuke Goto, Matt Switzler, Peng, Tzu-Hsiang, Bethany Connor, Jeremy Shimanek, Mark Byers, Avinash Amarnath, Xuebicoco, Rayo, Po Foon Kwong, Boffin, Jesse Jurman, Scott Markley, Elija Peterson, Ovidiu Mrd, paul g mohney, Steven Razey, Nathan Giusti, Helen Lee, Anthony Benedict, Karthik Balsubramanian, Annastasshia Ames, Amy Lopez, Vinh-Thuy Nguyen, Liz Candee, Ugur Doga Sezgin, Karmi Nguyen, John C. Vesey, and Yelena Baykova.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cognitive Load &amp; How the Brain REALLY Learns!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/LhPCIEas4GU</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LhPCIEas4GU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Found a Loophole to Survive the End of the Universe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VMm-U2pHrXE</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VMm-U2pHrXE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/nutshell to get 40% off unlimited access to Ground News so you can compare coverage and think critically about the news you read.

Sign up to the Birb’s Nest newsletter → https://shop.kgs.link/birb-nest 
Get exclusive freebies, early access, and much more from the kurzgesagt universe.

Sources & further reading:
https://sites.google.com/view/sources-surviveheatdeath/

Can we survive the heat death of the universe? One day, the last star will die, galaxies will dissolve, and black holes will evaporate. The universe becomes a cold, empty void where nothing happens. 
Forever. But there might be a loophole that lets life keep going.


OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤️ https://shop.kgs.link
Join the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of kurzgesagt soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook

The soundtrack of this video:
SoundCloud: https://bit.ly/4pMcMCn
Bandcamp: https://bit.ly/46Ik9SJ

If you want to help us caption this video, please send subtitles to subtitle@kurzgesagt.org
You can find info on what subtitle files work on YouTube here:
https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2734698?hl=en-GB&ref_topic=7296214
Thank you!


🐦🐧🐤 PATREON BIRD ARMY 🐤🐧🐦
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Many thanks to our wonderful Patreons (from http://kgs.link/patreon) who support us every month and made this video possible:
Anna Moser, Christian, Cody Merhoff, Elesvan JL, Eric Bodo, Ernest Burs, Gerard Sworn, Michał Zasępa, Romar Heesen, Viz]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Replacing Humans with AI is Going Horribly Wrong</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QX1Xwzm9yHY</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QX1Xwzm9yHY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:42:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">ColdFusion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://brilliant.org/coldfusion for 20% off the premium subscription, which grants you unlimited daily access to everything on Brilliant.

AI is a technology that divides people's opinions when we talk about its impacts. On the one had, AI has been disruptive to certain roles of employment. On the other hand, companies who have rushed to implement AI have found themselves regretting it. In this episode we get to the bottom of how AI is being used in the business world.

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1

Sources: 
https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cavjbsmufe42UwPWBJAZFnuIcML58SZR1I8g1CugCYA/edit?usp=drivesdk

ColdFusion Music: 

https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   

Get my book: 

http://bit.ly/NewThinkingbook 

ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Blind Spots of Platform Engineering • Matt McLarty &amp; Erik Wilde</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=swVM5soB1Os</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/swVM5soB1Os?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:53:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for GOTO Unscripted.
https://gotopia.tech

Read the full transcription of this interview here

Matt McLarty - CTO at Boomi & Co-Author of "Unbundling the Enterprise"
Erik Wilde - Principal Consultant at INNOQ

RESOURCES
Matt
https://bsky.app/profile/mattmclartybc.bsky.social
https://x.com/MattMcLartyBC
https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattmclartybc

Erik
https://www.linkedin.com/in/erikwilde
https://github.com/dret

Links
https://www.hbs.edu/faculty/Pages/profile.aspx?facId=6417
https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/application-development/richard-seroter-on-shifting-down-vs-shifting-left
https://platformengineering.org/blog

DESCRIPTION
Matt McLarty and Erik Wilde explore the nuanced world of platform engineering, challenging conventional approaches and highlighting the critical importance of aligning technological capabilities with business outcomes. They discuss the evolution from DevOps, the role of APIs, and the need to create flexible, reusable technological building blocks that drive true organizational innovation.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Stephen Fishman & Matt McLarty • Unbundling the Enterprise
 (https://amzn.to/3W2EcXw) Carliss Y. Baldwin • Design Rules, Vol. 2
 (https://amzn.to/4hdllRr) Matthew Skelton & Manuel Pais • Team Topologies
 (http://amzn.to/3sVLyLQ) Forsgren, Humble & Kim • Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps
 (https://amzn.to/3tCz1xO) Kim, Humble, Debois, Willis & Forsgren • The DevOps Handbook
 (https://amzn.to/47oAf3l) Gene Kim, Kevin Behr & George Spafford • The Phoenix Project (https://amzn.to/3X9cYxa) 
Crossing Borders (https://www.buzzsprout.com/2529297/episodes/17682252) 


Crossing Borders is a podcast by Neema, a cross border payments platform that...



Listen on: Apple Podcasts (https://podcasts.apple.com/podcast/id)    Spotify (https://open.spotify.com/show/2lOe2EyAuuvTnJjxqa1aav) 


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Nevada has so many ghost towns</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kg18CwWeMnc</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kg18CwWeMnc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:01:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Nevada is home to over 600 ghost towns, many of which are the remnants of the gold rush era of the 1800s and 1900s. Some of these ghost towns are well-known, like Rhyolite, but others are just coordinates on a map — hidden like secrets to the true history of Nevada.

Vox video producer Dolly Li road tripped through northern Nevada to try and find some of these hidden ghost towns and learn about the real history behind the boom and bust cycles of mining in the state. Along the way, she stops by a town that many call a ghost town, but is still partially occupied by a dozen residents.

Through visiting a few abandoned mining towns and speaking to historians about the technology and infrastructure that made mining a key industry of the state, we piece together a rich and fascinating story of Nevada’s development.

We had a chance to speak to a lot of great experts and historians for this video. Here are some links to their work:

Tami Force’s website, Nevada Ghost Towns & Beyond, where she’s documented hundreds of ghost towns in the state:
https://nvtami.com/

The archives of the W.M. Keck Earth Science and Mineral Engineering Museum (The Keck Museum), curated by Garrett J. Barmore, where we also conducted one of our interviews:
https://www.unr.edu/keck-museum

The Friends of Midas, a nonprofit organization currently run by Dana Bennett, that has a great collection of photos and history about the town of Midas:
https://friendsofmidas.com/

#ghosttowns #nevada #travel #roadtrip
This video is presented by Travel Nevada. Travel Nevada doesn’t have a say in our editorial decisions, but they make videos (and adventures!) like this one possible.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>